hey everyone thanks for listening to The
Grow Your Life podcast my name is
Jeremiah Kowski I'm excited this is
episode 301 we've been doing this for a
long time I've done weekly episodes for
the last 301 weeks and so I want to talk
this week about visualizing things and
what better time than episode 301 on
this one of the things that I think that
we end up doing way too often as
business owners is we end up Imagining
the worst case scenario we end up
planning and preparing for things to not
go well for us and unfortunately this
does not help us it does not produce the
kind of success it doesn't keep us safe
um what works
better is to imagine in your mind how
you would like things to go in every
scenario whether it be your Facebook ads
whether it be your relationship whether
it be a conversation with a spouse
whether it be how your evening will go
picking up the house or things like that
can I tell this our brain needs no help
coming up with the worst case
scenario and yet we naturally dwell on
that worst case scenario because we're
like well I don't want this to happen so
I'm so self-protective of making sure
that it never
happens and this becomes a vicious cycle
where literally our energy our focus our
mind our body our spirit everything
about us goes into that place of what
we're Imagining the most
most on the other side of it the same
thing
happens when you imagine good things
working out for you no matter what the
evidence is in the world around you no
matter what's going on around
you imagining that things are going to
work out they're going to go well for
you that they're going to happen in a
good way can I tell you this maybe
you've never done this
before try it shock yourself put it to
the test I promise you it's going to
change your life because this is the
number one thing that has changed my
life more than anything else every
Milestone that I've hit in my business
in my life comes from visualizing and
seeing the outcome and then feeling
internally imagining feeling allowing
the imagination of the experience to get
into my space to get into my thoughts my
feelings my relationship what I dwell on
what I think about I am imagine that the
best case scenario is going to happen
even in the toughest of situations even
in the most Dreadful of situations even
when things seem like they're going the
worst you you you start to imagine and
see it turning around in a better way
for
you and listen I
understand maybe some of you are like
Jeremiah you don't know my
situation I've had it too hard life is
has been too hard I can't do
that I I can't say that I know your
situation but I can say I've been
through hard things and this used to be
impossible for
me because I was always going based on
what I could see what was quote unquote
truth truthful in my life and I ended up
manifesting some of the worst case
scenarios that I that I ended up
imagining and what turned everything
around for me for my family for my life
I've seen this happen with multiple
people as well not just myself but
multiple people that what we visualize
becomes a reality and can I tell you
this is that right now everything that
you are experiencing in your life at
some point you saw it happening before
it started to happen you imagined either
to avoid it or that it would start to
happen everything that you ever created
in your life you imagined we have this
amazing visualization property in our
minds where we come up with and we
imagine and we see in our minds how
things are going to go before they
happen it's a it's something that all
human beings
do
and we do it to create our
world well we do it to create our world
positively or negatively and that's the
thing as most people are using it in a
way that's creating a negative world for
them it's creating a world that they
don't want to live
in and they're like well I've spent so
much time focusing on what I don't want
to happen to protect myself why do I
keep experiencing it and it becomes a
self-fulfilling
prophecy it becomes a repetitive pattern
that every time that we're like man I
don't want this bad thing to happen to
me
and then it
happens what if you tried something else
what if you
tried to do a risky thing because it
seems risky in the in the moment of it
and just
imagined what if it does work out what
if it does come together well for
me and I used to get angry when people
would say this to me and I used
to want to spit in their face and say
you don't know my situation you don't
know what's going on you don't know the
reality of what's
happening I wish I know what I know now
years
ago I wish I know and what I know now I
knew internally but I never experienced
it because I was too afraid to because I
was I was so caught up my nervous system
was constantly caught up in a state of
fight flight
freeze I was disregulated unregulated
in my nervous system my nervous system
was
so
Haywire operating in fear and worry and
lack and insecurity and trying to avoid
bad things from happening and then
literally every time I would say I
wanted to avoid a bad thing from
happening that thing ended up
happening and so what I started doing
was I started imagining what is the
beautiful life that I want to have
what what does that life feel like for
me and then all of those things not
overnight they didn't happen overnight
don't expect it to happen overnight but
it's a longterm what you put your focus
on will start to become your
reality this isn't woowoo
either this
is proven time time and time again in
every part of our Lives what are you
focusing on today where are you putting
your focus where are you putting your
energy and the next thing is is to start
to cultivate a sense of safety for
yourself where you feel safe imagining
great things happening where you feel
safe no matter what the situation is
because you find the safety not from
outside of you but from within
and that level changes
everything when we can create and
cultivate safety for ourselves and we
tell ourselves we tell our nervous
system we tell our trauma response I am
safe right
now no matter what's happening around
me I am safe even if the past situations
have told you that you're not safe in
said situation tell yourself that you
are and I'm not talking about like life
or death like you're in the in the face
of a an Axe Murderer or something like
that like of course run away from that
like or stay still or be quiet or
whatever you know it's the best thing to
do in that situation look like it's not
visualize that but when I talk about
sense of safety like I could be
experiencing something with my family
and not feel safe because it's replaying
a memory from my childhood where I
didn't feel safe but I'm no longer a
child I'm an adult I'm new situation so
I am safe and I'm creating that safety
I'm going Based On A Memory that's
telling
me I'm unsafe right now and then that
creates a reactivity a defensiveness
that creates a version of myself that I
don't like that shows up and that's
where I got to tell myself you're safe
in this situation what was going on in
your childhood is not what's happening
right now and that changes everything
for us changes
everything it'll happen in your business
will feel a sense of unsafety when we
launch Facebook ads when we put
ourselves out there to promote our
business and the only thing that creates
that safety is internally inside of us
it's a choice that we get to choose
based on how we talk to ourselves based
on how
we communicate to ourselves about
ourselves by loving
ourselves not in an arrogant way not in
a way that puts other people down but
rather kindness the same kindness that
we would offer somebody
else not being mean to ourselves but
loving and kind and compassionate and
giving ourselves
Grace and giving yourself a
break it'll change everything for you so
start imagining things going well for
you and then start reiterating anytime
you feel unsafe or and listen I'm I'm
telling you like the unsafety could be
can my wife made a comment about
something I feel unsafe because she had
to make a comment
oh but wait a sec I'm not in a situ I'm
not actually unsafe even if it feels
that way see what I mean that's what I'm
talking about and that changes
everything when we can start to realize
what's the truth the truth is that I am
safe in this
situation and that changes everything
all right so listen I hope that this
this has helped you these are some
lessons that have helped
me so tremendously over over the
years that will change your life if you
apply them if you start doing them if
you start just trying them
out things are going to go well for you
things are going to turn around no
matter what your situation
is and you're going to be looking back a
year from now saying wow
I wish I knew what I know now cuz that's
what I've been experiencing as well all
right grow your life everybody and we'll
talk soon
[Music]
[Applause]